# **Syed Ismailuddin**

### **Front End Developer**

A Front-End Developer with a strong Foundation in Technology and Frameworks of today's Standards like React.js, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Material UI, etc. My passion for user experience design allows me to create visually stunning and responsive websites that engage users. I also have an understanding of back-end technologies such as Node.js and Express, allowing me to effectively collaborate with back-end developers to build complex web applications.

- 🔀 smileyismail67@gmail.com
- <del>7</del> +91 8187050086
- smiley-ismail.netlify.app
- in linkedin.com/in/smileyismail
- github.com/smileyismail
- 🤱 Hyderabad, Telangana, India.



### Work Experience

#### 1) Dave Brother's - React.js Developer (Internship)

(November 2022 - March 2023)

- Developed and maintained multiple applications using React.js and Next.is
- Integrated with the backend technologies such as Node.js, Express.js, and Firebase.
- Collaborated with designers, project managers, and other developers to deliver projects on time and utilizing semantic methodologies and version control tools such as Git.

#### 2) V Cube Solutions - Front-End Developer (Contract)

(October 2021 - January 2022)

- Worked on the frontend part of full-stack projects that were built using Python and Java.
- Utilized advanced animations and designed various charts and graphs.
- Crafted comprehensive project documentation that captured every detail of the development process.



### **Skills**

- HTML / CSS
- JavaScript
- React JS
- Next JS
- Tailwind CSS
- Bootstrap
- Material UI
- Node JS / Express JS
- Git / Github



### Education

• **B. Tech** in Computer Science Engineering. JNTUH (2017 - 2022)



# **My Projects**

### 1) Pennywise 🔀

(React, Firebase, Tailwind CSS)

 Expense-tracking websites simplify financial management by providing an online platform for categorizing, tracking, and analyzing expenses, saving time and reducing errors.

## 2) Rasoi House 🔼

(React, Firebase, Tailwind CSS)

 A food delivery app that features authentication and a cart system, as well as different animations for a sleek UI.

## 3) Movies Hive 🔀

(React, Material UI, theMoviesDB)

 This website provides details and ratings of the movies, with new, popular, trending, and top-rated films constantly updated through a connection to an API.



#### Courses

- The Web-Developer
  Bootcamp 2022.
  Udemy
- The Complete
  JavaScript.
  Udemy
- React The Complete
  Guide.
  Udemy
- NodeJS- The Complete
  Guide.
  Udemy